TASEER SEER

Address: Villa 53b, Street 1b, Al Safa 1, Dubai Ph: +971503797163 Email:taseer.seer@gmail.com

Introduction

Senior Applications Engineer with over 17 years experience related to the Oil and Gas Industry. Varied Experience includes providing software related technical support to clients, building business cases, proposals, and technical presentations related to process engineering software. Experience also includes detailed design and FEED for Oil & Gas facilities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SIEMENS DIGITAL INDUSTRIES ABU DHABI, UNITED ARAB EMIRATES

Jan 2021 - Present

Senior Applications Engineer

Part of the Digital Industries Process Automation Software team that develops, oversees and provides consulting for gPROMS. gPROMS is an advanced process modelling and optimization tool that accelerates digitalization in the process industry. It helps build digital twins for processes in various industries, including energy, pharmaceuticals, and food and beverage providing sustainable solutions to clients worldwide.

- Job responsibilities include:
 - o Technical pre-sales activities including building business cases & presentations for potential clients or on wider forum such as exhibitions/conferences
 - o Building and presenting demonstrations of the software and its capabilities to potential and current clients
 - o Building proposals to bid on consulting projects for process safety studies, CFD analyses, and more
 - o Technical account management of existing clients including their license management, solving their day-to-day concerns with the product, and connecting them directly with developers for more detailed solutions
 - o Developing business by engaging and reaching out to potential clients and presenting solution capabilities
 - o Using technical knowledge of the energy sector, able to more accurately develop strategies to increase market share of solution
 - o Point of contact for any technical information regarding solutions in the Middle East region

PETROFAC INTERNATIONAL LIMITED SHARJAH, UNITED ARAB EMIRATES

Dec 2018 – Dec 2020

Senior Process Engineer

Major Client: ADNOC OFFSHORE

- Job responsibilities included:
 - o Managing Flow Assurance Analysis (Steady state and Transient) using OLGA software
 - o Overseeing equipment sizing and line hydraulics for entire plant
 - o Developing process design basis and design philosophies

ADNOC ONSHORE ABU DHABI, UNITED ARAB EMIRATES

Apr 2017 – Dec 2018

Senior Process Engineer

Part of In-house engineering team carrying out internal FEED and concept studies specializing in flow assurance.

- Job responsibilities included:
 - o Leading the process team in discussions with projects & other disciplines including workshops such as HAZOP/SIL
 - o Overseeing all process deliverables including PFDs, P&IDs, Hydraulic Analysis, Basis of Design
 - o Ensuring deliverables are issued on time and within specified manhours
 - o Setting out philosophies, scope of work, and reviewing all subcontracted Transient Analysis completed by contractor ensuring proper quality of work and verifiable results
 - o Reviewing all PSV/Control Valve calculations completed for the project
 - o Receiving technical queries from bidders and providing clarifications
 - o Reviewing Technical Bids from various bidders

Senior Process Engineer

Major Clients: Saudi Aramco, ENGIE

- Job responsibilities included:
 - o Leading the utilities section of the project
 - o Overseeing process calculations for Control valve/PSV calculations, Pump sizing
 - o Overseeing Instrument Air/Nitrogen demand/Fuel Gas Demand calculations
 - o Managing flare design with aim to minimize size of flare
 - o Development of project philosophies
 - o Development of process deliverables for utilities

PETROFAC INTERNATIONAL LIMITED SHARJAH, UNITED ARAB EMIRATES

September 2005 – July 2014

Senior Process Engineer

As part of the Process Engineering department learnt the use of OLGA software to carry out transient analysis; helped build an in house team to perform these activities avoiding the need to outsource these.

Major Clients: Saudi Aramco, KOC, ADNOC, Agip KCO, ISG

- Job responsibilities included:
 - o Performed HYSYS simulations to ensure equipment integrity after gas debottlenecking
 - Developed overall process simulation using HYSYS
 - Responding to queries from site and other disciplines including project management regarding the bases of various design issues
 - o Lead process team for variety of projects
 - o Developed Process Flow Diagrams (PFD), Utility Flow Diagrams (UFD), Safety Flow Diagrams (SFD) and Piping & Instrumentation Diagrams (P&ID)
 - Conducted Site Visits
 - o Performed technical bid evaluations to finalize vendors.
 - Performance tests execution
 - Provided operator training seminars
 - Review of the relief valve calculations used for design to ensure design integrity. This included the relief valve calculations, the relief valve inlet line size hydraulics, and preliminary relief valve tailpipe hydraulics. During this review, found undersized relief valves that have since been redesigned
 - o Managed and conducted flow assurance analysis for a variety of projects

EDUCATION

McMaster University, Hamilton, Canada

Sep 2000 - Jun 2004

Bachelor of Engineering – Chemical Engineering

TECHNICAL & COMPUTER SKILLS

- Well versed in Windows Operating Systems and MS Office
- Well versed in gPROMS, Aspen HYSYS, OLGA, PIPESIM, Aspen Flare System Analyzer and FLOWMASTER
- Working knowledge of PROMAX and HTRI

SOFT SKILLS TRAININGS

- Team Building
- Leadership

PERSONAL

Languages Fluent in English and Urdu

Nationality CanadianDate of birth May 24, 1981

Reference

References would be made available on request